I was thinking about my place in the universe,
كنت أفكر في مكاني في الكون
and about my first thought about what infinity might mean,
وحول فكرتي الأولى حول ما قد يعني اللانهاية
when I was a child.
عندما كنت طفلة
And I thought that if time could reach
واعتقدت أنه إذا كان الوقت قد يصل الى
forwards and backwards infinitely,
لامام والى الوراء بلا نهاية ،
doesn't that mean that
لا يعني ذلك أن
every point in time is really infinitely small,
كل نقطة في الوقت المناسب حقا هو متناه في الصغر ،
and therefore somewhat meaningless.
وبالتالي نوعا ما لا معنى لها.
So we don't really have a place in the universe,
لذلك نحن في الحقيقة ليس لنا مكان في الكون ،
as far as on a time line.
بقدر ما على خط الزمن.
But nothing else does either.
ولكن لا شيء آخر سواء.
Therefore every moment really is the most important moment
ولذلك كل لحظة هي في الحقيقة أهم لحظة
that's ever happened, including this moment right now.
التي قد تحصل أبد، بما في ذلك هذه اللحظة
And so therefore this music you're about to hear
وبالتالي هذه الموسيقى التي سوف تسمعوها
is maybe the most important music
ربما هي أهم موسيقى
you'll ever hear in your life.
ستسمعونها في حياتكم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق).
Thank you.
شكراً
For those of you who I'll be fortunate enough to meet afterwards,
لأولئك منكم الذين سأكون محظوظة بما فيه الكفاية للقاء لاحقاً
you could please refrain from saying,
أرجو منهم الإمتناع عن القول
"Oh my god, you're so much shorter in real life."
"يا إلهي ، أنت أقصر بكثير في واقع "
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Because it's like the stage is an optical illusion,
لأن المسرح يوحي إليك خطأ بصري
for some reason.
لبعض الأسباب
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Somewhat like the curving of the universe.
الى حد ما مثل التقويس الكوني.
I don't know what it is. I get asked in interviews a lot,
لا أعرف ما هو . يسألونني في المقابلات كثيراً ،
"My god, you're guitars are so gigantic!"
"!يا إلهي ، قيثاراتك هائلة لدرجة"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"You must get them custom made -- special, humongous guitars."
"يجب أن تجلبي لهم قيثارات أنيقة، خاصةً و عملاقة."
(Applause)
(تصفيق).
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم